<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Florian Oswald</title><link>https://floswald.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://floswald.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Florian Oswald</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 18:17:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://floswald.github.io/media/icon_hu_9d9b593248f3c06d.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://floswald.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Invisible Ties, Internal Flights: the Influence of Non-cohabiting Family on Migration Decisions</title><link>https://floswald.github.io/project/familymigration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 18:17:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/familymigration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every year, about 1 in 20 Americans move across cities. Extensive research has highlighted relevant frictions in geographic mobility, indicating constraints on individuals&amp;rsquo; ability to maximize professional, educational, or investment opportunities. While many migration decisions are driven by financial incentives, a notable proportion are influenced by family-related reasons. Crucially, some beneficial relocations might not occur due to preferences for staying close to relatives. Thus, family structures can either impede mobility, by adding to the costs of moving, or boost gross migration flows, as people relocate to be nearer to extended family members. Our paper is the first to estimate the value of living close to non-cohabiting family members — including parents, adult children, and siblings — and to discuss how much of the reluctance to move can be attributed to such preferences. Our analysis hinges on two primary data sources: the Panel Study of Income Dynamics (PSID), which tracks extended families and records their labor history, wealth, and expenditures, and confidential IRS tax data with intergenerational family linkages, providing a nationally representative longitudinal dataset. We empirically document that familial motives play a pivotal role in understanding frictions in geographic mobility and in decoding migration behaviors. Subsequently, we employ a detailed structural model to ascertain the familial component of moving expenses, which we find to be substantial. Furthermore, our findings indicate that alongside shifts in the geographical spread of job opportunities, alterations in family structures significantly contribute to the secular decline in migration trends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fiscal Policy for Climate Change</title><link>https://floswald.github.io/project/climate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 17:39:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/climate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fiscal policy offers a number of levers to reduce carbon emissions. Climate change mitigation can for example be implemented through carbon taxation on the production or consumption side, or through debt-financed public investments in emission-reducing infrastructure. Yet these various instruments may differ significantly in their cost-effectiveness in reducing emissions and in their distributional impacts among households. We develop a macroeconomic heterogeneous-agent model with environmental externalities to address both of these questions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fertility, Housing Costs and City Growth</title><link>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:15:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developed economies moved from a baby boom to a baby bust, with very low fertility in large urban centers. We develop a spatial theory of demographic change and urban growth, whereby the housing market acts as an endogenous automatic stabilizer of fertility: high housing costs deter fertility while lower demographic growth mitigates future housing price increase. Our theory predicts rich dynamics of fertility and housing costs across space and time. The aging of baby boomers and their sorting across space triggers a later baby bust, more pronounced in larger cities, together with a long-lasting fertility and house price cycle that varies across locations. The predictions of the theoretical model with endogenous demographics and city growth are confronted to the data for French urban areas over the last decades.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="status">Status&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Data Access: Confidential access data to the French Census&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Theory: We have a working model with joint location, fertility and housing choice. It delivers a closed form house price distribution in each city, equations for migration flows and an expression for the spending share on housing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Slides&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Data Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Draft&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>