<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Florian Oswald</title>
    <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://floswald.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Florian Oswald</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 17:39:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://floswald.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Bus Garages</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/buses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 17:39:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/buses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper estimates a spatial bus garage entry model to test whether anti-competitive market sharing agreements exist between firms in the London bus route procurement market. Our approach is based on a simple but powerful idea: a necessary condition for collusion is the triggering of a punishment when a firm deviates to the competitive equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiscal Policy for Climate Change</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/climate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 17:39:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/climate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fiscal policy offers a number of levers to reduce carbon  emissions. Climate change mitigation can for example be implemented through carbon taxation on the production or consumption side, or through debt-financed public investments in emission-reducing infrastructure. Yet these various instruments may differ significantly in their cost-effectiveness in reducing emissions and in their distributional impacts among households. We develop a macroeconomic heterogeneous-agent model with environmental externalities to address both of these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb vs Rents</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the causal impact of airbnb listings on long-term rents and house prices? In this project we try to establish a causal link between the two by using proprietary &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airdna.co&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;airdna&lt;/a&gt; data together with detailed rental market listings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;status&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Theory: We have a simple model to motivate the estimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Data Analysis: We wanted to use &lt;em&gt;terrorism&lt;/em&gt; as a demand shifter for airbnb tourism demand, didn&amp;rsquo;t work. currently looking for alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Draft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fertility, Housing Costs and City Growth</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project we want to better understand the role of fertility choices in the context of the standard Urban Model. How many children will be born in each location? Why is fertility different across cities? What is the role of fertility for city growth, over and above migratory flows alone? How could the literature on fertility think for so long about long run trends without considering the impact of children on the equilibrium house price? What&amp;rsquo;s the impact of the increasing shift in household composition towards smaller households for the house price distribution of different cities?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;status&#34;&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Data Access: Confidential access data to the French Census&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Theory: We have a working model with joint location, fertility and housing choice. It delivers a closed form house price distribution in each city, equations for migration flows and an expression for the spending share on housing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Data Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Draft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
